<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The "humble" blog of Philoponus Bindle</title>
<link href="https://philoponus.net"/>
<id>urn:uuid:95b20367-b6b8-4f66-9985-9c58d76aa8b6</id>
<updated>2020-06-05T12:16Z</updated>
<author><name>Philoponus Bindle</name></author>
<entry><title>The Dashboard</title>
<subtitle>Its Etymology and Function</subtitle>
<link href="https://philoponus.net/article/dashboard.html"/>
<id>urn:uuid:3b650a1b-5fb5-4c72-800e-acb1cfa1fdd9</id>
<updated>2020-06-05T12:16Z</updated>
<published>2020-02-03T12:00Z</published>
<content type="html">&lt;article>
&lt;h1>The Dashboard&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 class="subtitle">Its Etymology and Function&lt;/h2>

&lt;img class="main" src="../image/dashboard.png">

&lt;p>
When hearing the word "dashboard", perhaps two definitions spring to mind. The
first and most common is the dashboard of a car, with its instruments that
provide important but secondary information. The primary information being that
which is on the road itself, as of course it is more important when one is
driving that they do not hit the other cars on the road rather than obey the speed limit
to the specific digit. The other definition is the dashboard of a web app or similar,
which provides some condensed information about some system or service so
that it can be monitored. How truly useful that information is in a specific
dashboard is variable, many professionals relying heavily on some specific
dashboard, others being keenly aware that such-and-such a dashboard is utterly
useless.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
But the word "dashboard" itself used to have nothing to do with
displaying information. A folk etymology may go something like: a
dashboard is a board that information "dashes" to, or one that
someone can "read in a dash". Here dash conveys the meaning of speed or
quickness, but in dashboard's original usage dash was used to mean "hit",
such as in the phrase "the ship was &lt;em>dashed&lt;/em> against the rocks". The
dashboard was the board of the carriage that protected the passengers from the
mud that was kicked up by horses. It was a board for that mud to &lt;a href="https://www.etymonline.com/word/dashboard" title="dashboard at
    Etymology Online Dictionary">dash against&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
From that, the "dashboard" of a car comes naturally from its position in the
car which mirrored that of the dashboard of the carriage. While the dashboard
in a computer application comes thence by their common usage for
conveying information. Reasonable enough... but software dashboards as a tool evolved
before the term was applied to them. They were precursed by programs designed to provide
high-level data to executives for making business decisions (still a primary
purpose of the modern dashboard, although now not the only one), which— like
another overly-ambitious-and-ultimately-doomed-to-fail program concepts of the
80s: "expert systems"— was given a very literal named that ended in the very generic "systems", namely &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Executive_information_system">"executive
information systems"&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
So our conception of the sleek, modern, web app dashboard emerges from two veins of
history, one formal and one material. The latter gives it the lofty role of
providing all the critical information necessary to business executives needed
to make critical business-level decisions (note that "business-level" convokes
importance and significance, but also detachment, without detail,
corporate) and the former gives it the role of catching mud. The
analogy takes form: the dashboards conjoin and the information dashed
against our computer screens is seen for what it is, mud kicked up by horses.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
For the 19th century carriage driver though, it is the horses, the road, and the
carriage itself that they watch when driving. Even for the automobile driver
the dashboard is secondary. The experienced drivers watches the car and the road
first. But if the executives are as they would
like to position themselves in the metaphor of the carriage as the company,
as being the drivers of the cart, then they are not the proper, trained and elegant
carriage drivers purported, but rather has been inaugurated&lt;sup id="ref-1-1">&lt;a href="#note-1" title="On the word &quot;inaugurated&quot;">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>
as the corporate diviner, the hierophant who alone has the privilege to speak
with the gods. They in their folly try to read the patterns of mud on the
dashboard, patterns which must, as &lt;em>hard numbers&lt;/em> and &lt;em>descriptive
charts&lt;/em> must, give all the bits and pieces needed to turn the carriage left
or right, or hire and fire this employee or that, or work with some partner
company or another.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
And this is no trifle of a comparison! Businesses are no longer physical things,
but rather aggregates of arcane numbers. To the manager of the rank-and-file
worker, regardless of how many will purport otherwise, what matters is not the
person who is the worker themself, their skill and ability, their personality or candor.
No! All those are secondary. What matters is whatever arbitrary
measure of performance has been decided on by the manager or their
superiors.&lt;sup id="ref-2-1">&lt;a href="#note-2" title="On the word &quot;superior&quot;">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> Even when it is clear that
the numbers are meaningless, and admitted so by those using them, they must be
had. For to have no numbers is to be blind! There is no longer any other path
to understanding.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p class="quote">
No longer is the "measure" an approximation of the real, it is now the
&lt;strong>real itself!&lt;/strong>
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
And this applies equally to those above the manager, who invoke similar
measures, and then all the way up the priestly hierarchy to the executives and CEO, whose
decisions, companies and lives are ultimately at the whim of the one superior
number and measure to which all others are beholden: capital value. Normally,
for the company which does not have outside investors (be that in private 
or public markets), this is felt more directly, with revenue and
profit margins. But for the majority, these fluxes of capital value comes through a
strange machine with a plethora gauges, dials, buttons and gizmos. So many that one of
those experts of the stock market has taken to calling the movement of stock
prices a "Random Walk".
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
Of course, for all those professional investors whose esoteric methods of "analysis" are
&lt;a href="https://us.spindices.com/documents/spiva/spiva-us-year-end-2016.pdf?mod=article_inline" title="SPIVA U.S. Year-End 2016 Scorecard">not
sufficient to beat the index&lt;/a>, there are some who are blessed with the actual
ability to commune with the corporate gods. Of course this direct communication
with the gods of the stock market, those who cause tickers to rise and fall as
Luna does the tides, is condemned (when made public) as the blasphemous "insider
trading". But for the rest, those arcane numbers must be resorted to. That is
not to say that there is no place for pure fundamentalists (in both senses of
the word) to make money from these numbers, but regardless of this truth, the
relationship remains just between numbers: whether fundamentals translate to
making money or not does not change based on the reality of the company, but
numbers that are the fundamentals themselves. Not their basis in reality. For
the reality of what those numbers mean, and how they translate into the numbers
of one's growing coffers, have become as removed from reality an urban
astrologist who can no longer even find Venus in the night sky (or see it if
they found it) is disconnected from any astronomical (or even
astrological!) meaning. At least W.D. Gann was honest to his methodology.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
One of the great new tricks of the contemporary era is to make us all
think that we are investors.&lt;sup id="ref-3-1">&lt;a href="#note-3" title="">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>
Another is that executives are no more and we are all one family, giving the rest of us
in turn the faux appearance that we must be invested in the company's outcome to
the extent that an executive is, while failing in truth to give us their powers.
Or that we too can leverage the same awesome power of the stock market that the
Wall Street banker leverages, even though, as they say, "you gotta spend money
to make money", or equivalently, investments even when leveraged
multiplicatively can only make money proportional to the amount you initially
invest. The poor still are doomed to be poor. And as our retirement money is turned
into the loathsome tool for capitalist speculation that is the 401k and its ilk,
the corporate world teaches, through dashboards and propaganda, that we are the
numbers we see on the screen.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
Numbers are inculcated into the psyches of executives, managers and bankers
today as much as those of the call center worker who knows that if they do not
meet their quota they will be canned. They manifest in the factory worker (be it
a physical or mental factory) whose job was moved overseas (or underseas, back
into unconscious of the market) simply because it was cheaper to hire labor
there and ship whatever is produced back to its market, or in the grandmother
whose line of credit on her house intended as a stave against economic ruin was
only a source of increasing debt and increasing worry... But the system must do
this. It must extract the maximal amount of labor value and capital value
possible from people. If it were to do otherwise, if it were to try to have
compassion or to give people autonomy, it would undermine its own nature. It
would be denying its own truth, that there is no measure of happiness or success
other than net worth, the only number that makes anyone worthy of
anything.
&lt;/p>





&lt;hr>

&lt;footer id="notes">
&lt;h2>Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
    &lt;li id="note-1">
        &lt;p>
        An &lt;strong>in&lt;em>augur&lt;/em>ation&lt;/strong> is the formal ceremony by which
        one is inducted into an office of power. It is cognate with the English
        "augur" which both come through Latin from the PIE root &lt;a href="https://www.etymonline.com/word/*aug-?ref=etymonline_crossreference#etymonline_v_52551" title="*aug- at Etymology Online">*aug-&lt;/a>. The &lt;em>augur&lt;/em> was a
        role in Roman society who were diviners who worked by the motion birds,
        weather phenomena and how hens ate the feed spread on the ground for
        them. The connection to the word "&lt;em>au&lt;/em>thority" has an interesting
        twist too, for when the Roman general went into battle, the augur performed a
        sacrifice to determine the auspices for the battle's outcome. And if the
        auspices were not favorable, they would wait for the next day and then
        try again. Was the value of the augur to actually commune with some divinity?
        Well, if that divinity was Rome Herself. The dashboard designer and the augur
        both appeal to their own manifestations of divinity, the Executives who
        manifest the divinity of Capital and the Roman Emperor who manifests the divinity
        of Rome.
        &lt;/p>
        &lt;p>
        The further connections to the inauguration of our political figures,
        who each truly only exists as a symbol that extrudes the zeitgeist of their
        era, as the sceptre of authority itself and not its wielder, is not far behind.
        &lt;/p>
    &lt;/li>
    &lt;li id="note-2">
        &lt;p>
        For the authority of the corporate hierarchy
        implies superiority. But as this superiority comes from
        augury as much as from authority, it is entirely religious in nature.
        &lt;/p>
    &lt;/li>
    &lt;li id="note-3">
        &lt;p>
        Through the replacement of pension plans with 401ks that are investment
        tools, through the increase in employee stock options which give minimal
        amounts stock, and the rise of personal investment tools that purport to
        make investing a thing the whole family can enjoy.
        &lt;/p>
    &lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/footer>
&lt;/article></content>
<author><name>Philoponus Bindle</name></author>
</entry><entry><title>
The Necroscholastic
</title>

<link href="https://philoponus.net/article/necroscholastism.html"/>
<id>urn:uuid:62137a88-28c5-431a-a09d-cdeaadaaa3ee</id>
<updated>2020-06-10T23:18Z</updated>
<published>2020-06-10T12:00Z</published>
<content type="html">&lt;article>
&lt;h1>
The Necroscholastic
&lt;/h1>

&lt;div class="quote">
  &lt;p>
  It is in the nature of reason to perceive things truly, that is to say, as they
  are in themselves, that is to say, not as contingent but as necessary.
  &lt;/p>

  &lt;p>
  Hence it follows that it is through the &lt;em>imagination&lt;/em> alone that we
  look upon things as contingent both with reference to the past and the
  future.
  &lt;/p>

  &lt;div class="quote-name">
    &mdash;&lt;a href="https://www.gutenberg.org/files/31205/31205-h/31205-h.htm#Page_182">Baruch Spinoza&lt;/a>
  &lt;/div>
&lt;/div>

&lt;p>
I am not a scholastic. I am a necroscholastic. The scholars of our traditions
and histories, those upon which we are expected to comment or expound (and
today there is really only commentary) does not need to be reconciled with
anything, but rather resurrected. Born again in our own image. It is not my
intention to be particular to the intention of any author &mdash; which was the
vanity of the neoplatonists to reconcile Plato and Aristotle, which was the vanity
of the positivists to incorporate the mystical Wittgenstein into themselves
&mdash; but rather to construct my own meaning, my own figure of the past.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
This is no revision of the past, but rather it is the absence of the
stubbornness that leads to its revision! The past is not a solid thing: every
act of history is a construction, an act of will in the imagination, as much as
it is a work of archaeology.  And we have to construct to prefigure our future,
unconsciously or consciously. So I, longing for a another, better world,
choose to prefigure the future I desire. While beginning from them, I do not
necessarily to hold our ancestors or traditions in esteem: I transform them,
laud those I desire, and condemn those I despise.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
Recently, there has been some talk of toppling statues of confederate soldiers
&mdash; monuments to genocide, monuments that must be transformed through their
destruction &mdash; and from that some more talk of toppling the statues of
other "historical" figures, notably Christopher Columbus &mdash; that other
great symbol of American genocide. The response to the latter however, has been
less enthusiastic, it being likened to a denial of history, or a denial of the
history's nuance or its "greyness", and likened to the stagnation of history in
Orwell's &lt;em>1984&lt;/em> that comes from the Party's repression of the
possibility of change in the minds of its citizens... but this repression of
possibility is verily rather this conception that "history is too nuanced to
make real moral decisions about the characters of the past." That paralysis of
action that comes from the ever-contemplative and the indefinite suspension of
judgement. It is less important to me to take history within the context of the
past than it is to take it within the context of the future.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
Nuance can explain, but it does not excuse. This is true of ideology as well as
of tradition, philosophy as well as history. Do not tell me that the anarchist
excuses the antisemitism of Proudhon, or the thelemite the sexism of Éliphas
Lévi. So destroy, tear down the monuments to the past you detest, and resurrect
only those of you choose to.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
Though I sometimes read the scholastics, there is no need to really read them.
Only to resurrect their words in our own image: to transfigure the past into the
future that we desire. To take our traditions and interpret them in our own
image. To manifest in the images of the collective unconscious from which we
find ourselves expelled those of our conscious, those of our individuation from
the collective, and to will and to imagine, to make new collectives on the
frontier of the unconscious.
&lt;/p>



&lt;/article></content>
<author><name>Philoponus Bindle</name></author>
</entry><entry><title>Alice and Zooks</title>

<link href="https://philoponus.net/poem/alice-and-zooks.html"/>
<id>urn:uuid:40a26d1d-ad70-49e4-a75d-41052e053ccc</id>
<updated>2020-06-05T12:16Z</updated>
<published>2019-12-13T12:00Z</published>
<content type="html">&lt;article>
&lt;h1>Alice and Zooks&lt;/h1>

&lt;p>
Round the notsoround (mostly jagged) rock of swiveling shoally shore of the
stream-not-yet-a-river in banded banter Alice and Zooks juanted along most
merrily, to fritter away the times of their youth in a not unfounded fear of it
passing away, or of it becoming something else entirely.
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
"Pictures go into eyes, and words come out of the mouth, but they both go
through the head, which is why we can say things that refer to things."
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
"But whats in the head doing all that translating work? Seems awfully difficult
to me; I doubt I could do it if I set me mind upon it. And besides be that for
you the last time your head rattled around it sounded hollower than me
grandmother's bone marrow."
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
"But I spoke just before and you understood, verily so? Twould be a twiddle of
muppery muffins and then some if not!"
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
"Twould be, but twas a ghost that brought our bodies here to this stream, the
oeuvre of the day and of our heads!"
&lt;/p>

&lt;p>
With that the young Jungians of symbol galore brught theemselves forthswitcht to a
moorish mood, for they remembered that streams always turn to rivers lest they
run dry and fizzle to fuzz, and their filosophistical theories, the prowess and
profundity withwhich they betwixt them teenselves (though they be not more than
twelve and three quarters years or age) to surely be proof thereof. Yet theory
doesn't get one much farther than where one is always byandbye starting thereie,
which is why they forgot abot rivers going to oceans and then coming backtowhich
arond by way of tempertural or occult circumnavigation of the sky to feed fronds
or to be streams wunce again. By this reason twoo scientists have forgotten
about the application of science to nonscientific things, the rivers of their
work being pathways too grounded for water to evaporate off their regular
surfaces, even at the highest points of their tidal motion. Alas these two are
influential in their fields. But let us curl the stream of antipurposeful
digress to regress back upon itself to return to the subject(s) of Alice and
Zooks. They were not much in the way of scientists.
&lt;/p>



&lt;/article></content>
<author><name>Philoponus Bindle</name></author>
</entry></feed>